<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.5.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://adammusciano.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://adammusciano.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-11-13T20:32:35-05:00</updated><id>http://adammusciano.com/</id><title type="html">Adam.</title><subtitle>You know you wanna look :)</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Coding Livestream 4: Computer Vision on Public IP Cams</title><link href="http://adammusciano.com/2018/11/13/coding-livestream-4-computer-vision-on-public-ip-cams/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Coding Livestream 4: Computer Vision on Public IP Cams" /><published>2018-11-13T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-11-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://adammusciano.com/2018/11/13/coding-livestream-4-computer-vision-on-public-ip-cams</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://adammusciano.com/2018/11/13/coding-livestream-4-computer-vision-on-public-ip-cams/">&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/xS0nCT0yrfg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In this stream I cover how to harvest IP cameras for computer vision exercises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Adam Musciano</name></author><summary type="html">In this stream I cover how to harvest IP cameras for computer vision exercises.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Coding Livestream 3: Let’s Learn About YARA</title><link href="http://adammusciano.com/2018/11/13/coding-livestream-3-let-s-learn-about-yara/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Coding Livestream 3: Let's Learn About YARA" /><published>2018-11-13T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-11-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://adammusciano.com/2018/11/13/coding-livestream-3-let-s-learn-about-yara</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://adammusciano.com/2018/11/13/coding-livestream-3-let-s-learn-about-yara/">&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/rNeFrY2OGdQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In this stream I go over the way YARA rules work and how to apply them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Adam Musciano</name></author><summary type="html">In this stream I go over the way YARA rules work and how to apply them.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Coding Livestream 2: Let’s Deploy an SSH Honeypot</title><link href="http://adammusciano.com/2018/11/13/coding-livestream-2-let-s-deploy-an-ssh-honeypot/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Coding Livestream 2: Let's Deploy an SSH Honeypot" /><published>2018-11-13T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-11-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://adammusciano.com/2018/11/13/coding-livestream-2-let-s-deploy-an-ssh-honeypot</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://adammusciano.com/2018/11/13/coding-livestream-2-let-s-deploy-an-ssh-honeypot/">&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Xf9g7npdHAY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In this stream I deploy an SSH Honeypot called Cowrie&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Adam Musciano</name></author><summary type="html">In this stream I deploy an SSH Honeypot called Cowrie</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Coding Livestream 1: Find Every Arby’s in America</title><link href="http://adammusciano.com/2018/11/13/coding-livestream-1-find-every-arby-s-in-america/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Coding Livestream 1: Find Every Arby's in America" /><published>2018-11-13T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-11-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://adammusciano.com/2018/11/13/coding-livestream-1-find-every-arby-s-in-america</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://adammusciano.com/2018/11/13/coding-livestream-1-find-every-arby-s-in-america/">&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/B4PBqh0OW8I&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In this stream I work on scraping Arby's location information. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Adam Musciano</name></author><summary type="html">In this stream I work on scraping Arby's location information.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">On the future of Apps</title><link href="http://adammusciano.com/2017/08/07/on-the-future-of-apps/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On the future of Apps" /><published>2017-08-07T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-08-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://adammusciano.com/2017/08/07/on-the-future-of-apps</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://adammusciano.com/2017/08/07/on-the-future-of-apps/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-death-of-the-app-as-we-know-it&quot;&gt;The Death of the App as We Know It&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As phone technology progressed, apps became the standard for deploying neatly packaged software to the end user. With the data saved locally and the size of average app constantly increasing, phone manufacturers were forced to focus on storage as a main feature of a phone. Batteries became thinner, storage became lighter – but we’ve reached a standstill that calls for a different approach instead of upgraded parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mobile apps rely on bulky software being stored on the client of the phone. The focus on client side data has major benefits, but at this point I think many of the benefits have been  outgrown. One big pro to a focus on client side apps is availability. Because all of the data is stored locally, it can be accessed anywhere. During the days where phone signal was very slow and less widely available, this approach made sense. Users would need access to services during times with no signal, so naturally developers would want their apps stored locally for the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This becomes an issue when the data is unneeded. For example, you will never need to use a banking app without a wireless connection, so why should it be taking up memory on our phone when we don’t need it? It’s unused space for a service that might not be needed frequently. This goes for many apps that don’t serve a purely offline purpose. Quite simply, these apps are taking up too much space – and we have too many of them. The amount of apps we store directly on our phones adds to the problem. Many of these apps have dependencies that directly overlap, but need to be installed on a per-instance basis. So on a phone, there might be 60 apps, and only 5 of them get used daily. then maybe 40 apps that are used at some point within a week, and 15 that are very rarely used. This is a huge amount of unneeded clutter that could directly be fixed by a change of approach in software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, we’ve come to a point where phone users have signal in most places. In the near future, signal coverage will expand and become faster. I think that a point will be reached where the speeds of satellite data becomes a practical solution for the majority of end-users. With 4g speeds being close to speeds of wireless data transfer, the rates are fast enough to cover most media consumption. This type of streaming approach allows for a much more flexible design in hardware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To paint a clearer picture about how this change in approach might benefit others, I’ve created an example:
  I have one powerful desktop hooked up with gigabit ethernet and fast transfer rates. This computer is always on and handles most of my day-to-day tasks.. But what if I’m on the go? Well, I have a remote desktop service constantly running on the machine, so if I ever need to get on it, I can &lt;b&gt;stream&lt;/b&gt; my connection from anywhere with good enough internet. This allows me to have the power of a full-fledged desktop on any machine with enough of an internet connection. I can have raspberry pi’s scattered throughout the world, and I now have a high performance desktop tailored to my liking wherever I go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This approach is highly scalable, and already has been used effectively by developers. Instead of customers buying an expensive computer that they need to replace or upgrade in a few years, they could purchase a subscription to a powerful server that scales in processing and storage as the user needs it, so they are never paying for too much or too little. The user would need to buy a much cheaper streaming device with long battery life and a large screen, while saving room/money on storage, memory, and processing. The streaming devices could be highly diverse, as remote desktop services are available on most operating systems already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it is cheaper, faster, lighter, and exact – but what is the cost? Security, Privacy, and  Accessibility are the  main issues that I think could cause harm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This design effectively centralizes all user data into one area/company, which many would see as a bad thing. It’s like hiding all of your money under your bed – if a thief finds it, you’re screwed. With the recent IWannaCry virus shutting down hospitals around Europe, it could be argued that a huge remote desktop web service would be highly vulnerable to that sort of attack, which could permanently damage customer’s data. This is true, but the remote desktop providers could effectively guard against this by automatically updating their customers operating system and security to the latest software, which many customers would not do if they had a physical computer instead. When looked at like this, it could be seen as a safer more secure approach – while people would be getting individually hacked less, the company would be targeted much more frequently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another problem with the centralization of personal computers is that you no longer truly own your data. At the very least, companies will be monitoring your activity on these remote computer subscriptions. But, it could be much worse – If the company decided to become malicious, the data could be used to blackmail and exploit people. This &lt;b&gt;should&lt;/b&gt; be the biggest issue among consumers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, accessibility would be hindered. This design is strongly based in accepting that if you don’t have internet, you’re not going to be able to use your computer. In a world where everyone used satellite streaming when without internet connection, ths wouldn’t be that big of a deal. But, it definitely isn’t for everyone. Chromebooks have the same caveat, following a very similar streaming design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that these negatives are already problems for most users, and because of that, this is a viable design that allows for a lot more mobility at cheaper prices. Time to say goodbye to apps, the future is streaming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me know what you think!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/drXNPy23Xco&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This youtube video covers a lot of what I talk about&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Adam Musciano</name></author><summary type="html">The Death of the App as We Know It</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Linux Tips: Easy Aliases</title><link href="http://adammusciano.com/2017/08/01/linux-tips-easy-aliases/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Linux Tips: Easy Aliases" /><published>2017-08-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-08-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://adammusciano.com/2017/08/01/linux-tips-easy-aliases</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://adammusciano.com/2017/08/01/linux-tips-easy-aliases/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-is-an-alias&quot;&gt;What is an Alias?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An alias is a global variable set by linux that can be freely called in terminals and scripts once defined. For example, if a user enters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;  alias weather='curl wttr.in/cancun' 

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;there will now be an alias called weather in that session which calls a service to get the weather in cancun. One think to be careful with when defining an alias is the whitespace – an alias definition must be called as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;  alias &amp;lt;aliasname&amp;gt;='&amp;lt;text-to-store&amp;gt;'
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve tried this, you might find that once you exited your session, the aliases were gone the next time you came back.So, how do you get around this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;messing-with-the-configs&quot;&gt;Messing with the Configs&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most common way to make aliases persistent between sessions is to define them in the config file of your terminal. I personally use zsh, so my config file is named .zshrc in the root folder. This file runs absolutely anytime I open my terminal or call zsh. Because it is the first thing to run when I open a terminal, it is the best place to define my aliases. You can either append them directly into the file, or have all your aliases contained in a file that you run in the config.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make it a little clear, I’ll explain what it might look like. First, I got to my root directory and create a file called .aliases.sh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt; echo &quot;&quot; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; ~/.aliases.sh
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I’ll append an alias into the file with my favorite text editor. I will add the weather alias we went over at the begginning. With the alias file preloaded with code that is ready to be executed, it is time to call it in the terminal config file. So, I go into my .zshrc file, and append ‘’’ source ~/.aliases.sh ‘’’ to the end of the file. Save the file, and great! Now you have all your aliases neatly placed in one file that can be added to whenever you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;useful-aliases&quot;&gt;Useful Aliases&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a list of some of my aliases that might be useful to you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;# reboot / halt / poweroff
alias reboot='sudo /sbin/reboot'
alias shutdown='sudo /sbin/shutdown -t now'

#volume controls
alias volset='amixer sset Master '
alias volup='amixer sset Master 5%+'
alias voldown='amixer sset Master 5%-'

alias volmute='amixer -D pulse sset Master mute'
alias volmute='amixer -D pulse sset Master unmute'

#weather
alias weather=&quot;curl wttr.in/cancun&quot;

# update on one command
alias update='sudo apt-get update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo apt-get upgrade'

#internet speeds
alias speedtest='curl -s  https://raw.githubusercontent.com/sivel/speedtest-cli/master/speedtest.py | python -'

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;a-brief-warning&quot;&gt;A Brief Warning&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While aliases can save a lot of time, they can also be used exessively. If you find yourself having trouble working on other systems that don’t have your aliases defined, you might be using too many. While it is simple to copy your alias file over to other computers (especially if you host your dotfiles with github), there may be times where they just aren’t available to you. Use aliases responsibly, folks.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Adam Musciano</name></author><summary type="html">What is an Alias?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Goodwill Chest Upgrade - Part 2 Electric Boogaloo</title><link href="http://adammusciano.com/2017/07/21/goodwill-chest-part-2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Goodwill Chest Upgrade - Part 2 Electric Boogaloo" /><published>2017-07-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://adammusciano.com/2017/07/21/goodwill-chest-part-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://adammusciano.com/2017/07/21/goodwill-chest-part-2/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;well-that-took-a-while&quot;&gt;Well that took a while!!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8 months later, and I’m still working on this project. In quick summary, I’ve finished everything but the electric parts, and most of the ideas for the project have changed. In this post, I will cover what goals have changed, the supplies that have been added or removed, and an estimated price of the project so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-goals&quot;&gt;The Goals&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To Create a nice Bench for the balcony in the warmer months&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;s&gt;To Create a nice Table for the living room in the colder months&lt;/s&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My roommates realized our apartment won’t let us give them back furniture that they supplied. There’s not much room to hide away a spare table, so the chest will have to stay outside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of the goals have changed, so here is the updated goal log:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most Important&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Weather Resistant&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reinforced Structure&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Speakers, via aux cord&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;USB charging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Optional&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Amazon Echo support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;supplies&quot;&gt;Supplies&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this wasn’t exactly meant to be a budget build, it turned out that way. In total, I have only spent 26$ on this project. It is at a point now where I am satisfied with it aesthetically, and the lack of power tools made my decision much easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Supplies List is as Follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One Big Chest  – $13&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cabernet Wood Stain – $12&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Carpet – found some around the apartment complex&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wooden Pallet – may have accidentally stolen it from the groundskeepers of the complex.. Sorry, I thought it was trash!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nails – I really should’ve bought nails. I’ve been recycling what I can from the pallets, it works but its not pretty.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Removing the Paint&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After receiving input from the kind people who listen to my nonsense, I decided it might look good to chip the old paint off and add a stain. So, I started chipping…and chipping.. and chipping. For about 3 months. This process could/should have been much faster, but after finding out the neighbors didn’t enjoy hearing my 10 am chiseling sessions, I decided to wait until it got warmer so I could work outside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While chiseling, I found a small metal badge, which I later found out was a list of patents. It turns out that this chest is from the beginning of the 1900’s! After searching for the patent logs, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?tbo=p&amp;amp;tbm=pts&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;q=ininventor:%22Eugene+W+Hawley%22&quot;&gt;I found it, and the inventor.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reinforcing the Chest&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After removing the thin veneer from the sides and top of the chest, I noticed that it had become significantly less sturdy. I decided to reinforce the top of the chest by nailing a few planks across the inside. Fortunately I found a wooden pallet in the apartment complex’s garbage, I took it apart and denailed it up on the balcony. After some use, I think I will need to do a better job nailing these in – the top is slightly bowed now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Staining the Chest&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the chest reinforced and ready to go, all that was left was to make it a little prettier. I ended up using a cabernet wood stain that I found at Michael’s. It was much thicker than the liquid stains I’ve used before, which helped with not accidentally staining my balcony and it’s walls, but in turn was much harder to spread.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Finished” Project&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this is by no means the final design, it is at a point where I think I can say it serves a purpose and is no longer a work in progress. While it is not realistic to be used as an indoor table, the goals of the project changed and in the end I’m statisfied with how it’s turned out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Future Ideas&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, the chest is good as-is for use as a bench or table, and the inside is used as storage. In the future, I would like to work more on the inside of the chest to give it speakers. I had found a mini fridge that I thought could be converted into something like a small kegorator to be put inside with a tap on the outer side, but decided it would not be worth the additional weight and resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aesthetically, I like the looks but I think I’d like to now work on wood burning designs into the sides. First I need to find/make a woodburner, but this is definitely going to happen at some point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Patent: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?tbo=p&amp;amp;tbm=pts&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;q=ininventor:%22Eugene+W+Hawley%22&quot;&gt;patentLink&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Adam Musciano</name></author><summary type="html">Well that took a while!!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cool New Job</title><link href="http://adammusciano.com/2017/01/23/cool-new-job/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cool New Job" /><published>2017-01-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-01-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://adammusciano.com/2017/01/23/cool-new-job</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://adammusciano.com/2017/01/23/cool-new-job/">&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;b&gt;Being geeky in Petco ended up getting me my dream job&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;job-description&quot;&gt;Job Description&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am working under a Professor that has assigned me to designing the setup of the currently empty lab meant for doing tests on sps coral. The experiments may change over time, so the system needs to be able to handle many different circumstance. Automation is a big concern, all information should be highly accurate and highly accessible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In High School, I would have told you that a position like this would be my dream job. It seems very ironic that I would end up getting a job doing everything I had wanted in a job when I was younger, at a time when I didn’t know jobs like these &lt;em&gt;even existed&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had first heard of the job through a woman in passing, who had overheard me talking to my roommate about coral. She introduced herself as a grad student, and said they were looking for someone with the experiences and goals that I had. I am very grateful for this person, you can check out her portfolio website &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.allisymbiosis.com/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&quot;//giphy.com/embed/AW2FY8fUL1QHu?hideSocial=true&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;246&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;It's easy to see the allure to reef keeping with species such as this&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;prior-experiences&quot;&gt;Prior Experiences&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the summer before my freshman year of High School, I started my first Marine Reef Aquarium. Turning my parent’s basement into a 14 year old’s skewed depiction of a laboratory (thanks Mom and Dad!), I started to foster a reef aquarium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those aware of the many acronyms and terminologies of reef keeping, I grew three types of coral: some soft, few lps, and many sps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tank let me experiment and learn about many different skills that I normally wouldn’t have been exposed to – especially at such a young age. Reef keeping didn’t just educate me in specifics that might only help in academia (spectroscopies, water chemistry, etc), but it taught me more about the world around me. I think it gave me a more inquisitive perspective of nature, and taught me not to fear seemingly “big” tasks, and instead to break them down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reef keeping also gave me my first entrance into practical programming. No more Right triangle calculators, card games, or magic 8 ball scripts – now my fish and coral’s lives relied on my code to work flawlessly. From scripts to mimic the times of moonlight vs. sunlight during the year, to scripts to help automate maintenance of the tank, I learned about how much utility there is to learning a programming language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To give you a picture of how important the health of coral is to some hobbyists, &lt;a href=&quot;http://uniquecorals.com/coral/sps/acropora-sp-jason-fox-fox-flame-acro-3-wysiwyg-grwout-colony.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; is a listing for 3 inches of a collector’s edition acropora, priced at 900$.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&quot;//giphy.com/embed/mLmURHYltc7Dy?hideSocial=true&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Yes, these are real&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Adam Musciano</name></author><summary type="html">Being geeky in Petco ended up getting me my dream job</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Goodwill Chest Upgrade</title><link href="http://adammusciano.com/2017/01/19/goodwill-chest/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Goodwill Chest Upgrade" /><published>2017-01-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-01-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://adammusciano.com/2017/01/19/goodwill-chest</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://adammusciano.com/2017/01/19/goodwill-chest/">&lt;style&gt;
@media ( min-width: 768px ) {
    .grid-divider {
        position: relative;
        padding: 0;
    }
    .grid-divider&gt;[class*='col-'] {
        position: static;
    }
    .grid-divider&gt;[class*='col-']:nth-child(n+2):before {
        content: &quot;&quot;;
        border-left: 1px solid #DDD;
        position: absolute;
        top: 0;
        bottom: 0;
    }
    .col-padding {
        padding: 0 15px;
    }
}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;b&gt;A search for cheap Goodwill sweaters led me to 0 sweaters and 1 chest too big to fit in my car.&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;container&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;row grid-divider&quot;&gt;

        &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-4&quot;&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;col-padding&quot;&gt;  
            &lt;p&gt;4 days ago, I bought a 13$ rusty/chipped chest from Goodwill. I had no plans when I bought it, and no expectations for it other than as a bench for my apartment balcony. But, as my roommate and I were trying to fit this oversized crate into my car, I came up with some interesting ideas for it.
            &lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-4&quot;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;col-padding&quot;&gt;
                &lt;img src=&quot;/img/goodwill-chest/post-goodwill-chest-closed.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-goals&quot;&gt;The Goals&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To Create a nice Bench for the balcony in the warmer months&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To Create a nice Table for the living room in the colder months&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goals in their designated immediacy are…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most Important&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Convenient way to transport&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Surround sound / device network connectivity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Controlled Speakers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Easy access to inside storage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aesthetic repairs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;USB charging&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cooler for iced beverages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Optional&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Amazon Echo support&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Temperature display&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;supplies&quot;&gt;Supplies&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of now, I’m fairly clueless on what I’m going to need. I’ll be buying things as I need them, and will be recycling old parts as much as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Supplies List is as Follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One Big Chest&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An old computer power supply&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I know, not much to go off of. These items may be replaced by other things depending on what makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/img/goodwill-chest/post-goodwill-psu.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;idea&quot;&gt;Idea&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to chip the paint off of all sides, exposing the raw wood. After that, my thoughts were to either stain the raw wood, paint it black again, or leave it raw and have friends paint over it. Here is a poll for your opinions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot; src=&quot;//www.websitegoodies.com/poll.php?id=114229&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far Ive scraped some of the paint off the sides. It is very dry, it cracks off in some places when I’m lucky. I’ll be buying a chisel ASAP, an old pocket knife and some sandpaper isn’t cutting it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/img/goodwill-chest/post-goodwill-chest-side-sanded.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also cut out most of the old floral canvas on the inside, leaving the exposed wood. &lt;strong&gt;Very&lt;/strong&gt; dusty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/img/goodwill-chest/post-goodwill-chest-inner.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the electronics, I’d like to mount some sort of power to the inside and allow for the chest itself to plug in to a wall outlet for power. This way it can be run permanently during the winter, and turned on when needed in the summer. A power strip might be the easiest solution; a battery would be inconvenient for this application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan to put the speakers on both sides of the chest, mostly because I think it would look aesthetically pleasing. As of now, this is planned to be controlled by a raspberry pi with a wifi and bluetooth dongle so devices can connect, and it can stream. I may also look at separate solutions that avoid using an ARM processor, as it can be inconvenient due to most software being 32bit/64bit dependent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have no idea how this will turn out, or if I will need to throw it out. But for 13$ and some old parts, its worth a shot. I’ll be giving updates in new posts as I go.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Adam Musciano</name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">QR Guitar Experiment</title><link href="http://adammusciano.com/2017/01/04/qr-guitar-experiment/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="QR Guitar Experiment" /><published>2017-01-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-01-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://adammusciano.com/2017/01/04/qr-guitar-experiment</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://adammusciano.com/2017/01/04/qr-guitar-experiment/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;inception&quot;&gt;Inception&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first guitar was a beat up acoustic American Standard that had been through many years of not-so-great care. The nut was cracked, the body was badly scratched, and vastly changing temperatures caused the guitar to warp. Throughout the years, I ended up getting new guitars, and my first went to the wayside, left to hang in my room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first started driving, I had romanticized the idea of going throughout the country in my late great-step-grandmother’s brown Honda 03’ CRV that my family had jokingly named the “Polished Turd”. I felt like just driving for the sake of exploring wasn’t enough, and that I needed some sort of mission or goal for the trip. I wanted to go alone, and meet new people on the way – To share ideas, laughs, and music. So, to sum up all of those goals, I came up with the QR Guitar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-idea&quot;&gt;The Idea&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to create a “living” guitar – an instrument that would pick up history on it’s way wherever it went, and transmit it’s history to the people who saw it. So, I decided I would put quotes that were meaningful to me on the body of the guitar, and the names of the people who came up with them on the neck. By putting a QR Code on the pickguard, anyone with a smartphone could scan it to get more information. The QR Code led to &lt;a href=&quot;http://mooseprojects.wixsite.com/qrguitar&quot;&gt;a website I created&lt;/a&gt; that would document where the guitar has been, and who had played it. People who visited the website could share their experience with the guitar, giving my once old and bland guitar a new life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;working-on-the-guitar&quot;&gt;Working on the Guitar&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite Frankly, I had no idea what I was doing. I made every mistake possible, from misquoting people to sanding against the grain of the wood to spilling wood glue all over the body. Luckily, I learned along the way and didn’t make any mistakes that totally ruined the instrument. It taught me a lot, and in the end I was left with an acoustic guitar that had real, hard-earned character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/img/post-qrGuitar-GIF.gif&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;wheres-it-been&quot;&gt;Where’s it Been?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The QR Guitar has travelled with me throughout most of the east coast, which I could never have imagined happening. People are always receptive to the idea of the guitar and tend to ask questions, although not many end up playing it. Lately it has been hanging where it was years before on a wall, waiting for another adventure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;future-goals&quot;&gt;Future Goals?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the guitar’s main purpose is still relevant today, and could see myself giving it away someday. I would love to see someone take the guitar and travel to new places with it, meeting and influencing new and different people along the way. That would be the ultimate reward, to see the ‘living’ QR Guitar thriving in new environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to see what has happened with this guitar, please go to: &lt;a href=&quot;http://mooseprojects.wixsite.com/qrguitar&quot;&gt;http://mooseprojects.wixsite.com/qrguitar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Y2XEQ0lDrfg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Adam Musciano</name></author><summary type="html">Inception My first guitar was a beat up acoustic American Standard that had been through many years of not-so-great care. The nut was cracked, the body was badly scratched, and vastly changing temperatures caused the guitar to warp. Throughout the years, I ended up getting new guitars, and my first went to the wayside, left to hang in my room.</summary></entry></feed>