<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="http://adammusciano.com/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://adammusciano.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://adammusciano.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-01-23T15:10:13-05:00</updated><id>http://adammusciano.com//</id><title type="html">Adam.</title><subtitle>Full Stack? Yeah, maybe kinda.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Cool New Job</title><link href="http://adammusciano.com/2017/01/23/cool-new-job/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cool New Job" /><published>2017-01-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-01-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://adammusciano.com/2017/01/23/cool-new-job</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://adammusciano.com/2017/01/23/cool-new-job/">&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;b&gt;I was being a geek in Petco, and ended up getting my old &quot;dream&quot; job &lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;job-description&quot;&gt;Job Description&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am working under a Professor that has assigned me to designing the setup of the currently empty lab meant for doing tests on sps coral. The experiments may change over time, so the system needs to be able to handle many different circumstance. Automation is a big concern, all information should be highly accurate and highly accessible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In High School, I would have told you that a position like this would be my dream job. It seems very ironic that I would end up getting a job doing everything I had wanted in a job when I was younger, at a time when I didn’t know jobs like these &lt;em&gt;even existed&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had first heard of the job through a woman in passing, who had overheard me talking to my roommate about coral. She introduced herself as a grad student, and said they were looking for someone with the experiences and goals that I had. I am very grateful for this person, you can check out her portfolio website &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.allisymbiosis.com/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&quot;//giphy.com/embed/AW2FY8fUL1QHu?hideSocial=true&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;246&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;It's easy to see the allure to reef keeping with species such as this&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;prior-experiences&quot;&gt;Prior Experiences&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the summer before my freshman year of High School, I started my first Marine Reef Aquarium. Turning my parent’s basement into a 14 year old’s skewed depiction of a laboratory (thanks Mom and Dad!), I started to foster a reef aquarium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those aware of the many acronyms and terminologies of reef keeping, I grew three types of coral: some soft, few lps, and many sps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tank let me experiment and learn about many different skills that I normally wouldn’t have been exposed to – especially at such a young age. Reef keeping didn’t just educate me in specifics that might only help in academia (spectroscopies, water chemistry, etc), but it taught me more about the world around me. I think it gave me a more inquisitive perspective of nature, and taught me not to fear seemingly “big” tasks, and instead to break them down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reef keeping also gave me my first entrance into practical programming. No more Right triangle calculators, card games, or magic 8 ball scripts – now my fish and coral’s lives relied on my code to work flawlessly. From scripts to mimic the times of moonlight vs. sunlight during the year, to scripts to help automate maintenance of the tank, I learned about how much utility there is to learning a programming language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To give you a picture of how important the health of coral is to some hobbyists, &lt;a href=&quot;http://uniquecorals.com/coral/sps/acropora-sp-jason-fox-fox-flame-acro-3-wysiwyg-grwout-colony.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; is a listing for 3 inches of a collector’s edition acropora, priced at 900$.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&quot;//giphy.com/embed/mLmURHYltc7Dy?hideSocial=true&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;270&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Yes, these are real&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Adam Musciano</name></author><summary type="html">I was being a geek in Petco, and ended up getting my old &quot;dream&quot; job</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Goodwill Chest Upgrade</title><link href="http://adammusciano.com/2017/01/19/goodwill-chest/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Goodwill Chest Upgrade" /><published>2017-01-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-01-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://adammusciano.com/2017/01/19/goodwill-chest</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://adammusciano.com/2017/01/19/goodwill-chest/">&lt;style&gt;
@media ( min-width: 768px ) {
    .grid-divider {
        position: relative;
        padding: 0;
    }
    .grid-divider&gt;[class*='col-'] {
        position: static;
    }
    .grid-divider&gt;[class*='col-']:nth-child(n+2):before {
        content: &quot;&quot;;
        border-left: 1px solid #DDD;
        position: absolute;
        top: 0;
        bottom: 0;
    }
    .col-padding {
        padding: 0 15px;
    }
}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;b&gt;A search for cheap Goodwill sweaters led me to 0 sweaters and 1 chest too big to fit in my car.&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;container&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;row grid-divider&quot;&gt;

        &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-4&quot;&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;col-padding&quot;&gt;  
            &lt;p&gt;4 days ago, I bought a 13$ rusty/chipped chest from Goodwill. I had no plans when I bought it, and no expectations for it other than as a bench for my apartment balcony. But, as my roommate and I were trying to fit this oversized crate into my car, I came up with some interesting ideas for it.
            &lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-4&quot;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;col-padding&quot;&gt;
                &lt;img src=&quot;/img/goodwill-chest/post-goodwill-chest-closed.jpg&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-goals&quot;&gt;The Goals&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To Create a nice Bench for the balcony in the warmer months&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To Create a nice Table for the living room in the colder months&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goals in their designated immediacy are…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most Important&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Convenient way to transport&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Surround sound / device network connectivity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Controlled Speakers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Easy access to inside storage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aesthetic repairs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;USB charging&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cooler for iced beverages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Optional&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Amazon Echo support&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Temperature display&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;supplies&quot;&gt;Supplies&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of now, I’m fairly clueless on what I’m going to need. I’ll be buying things as I need them, and will be recycling old parts as much as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Supplies List is as Follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One Big Chest&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An old computer power supply&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I know, not much to go off of. These items may be replaced by other things depending on what makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/img/goodwill-chest/post-goodwill-psu.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``
————————–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;idea&quot;&gt;Idea&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to chip the paint off of all sides, exposing the raw wood. After that, my thoughts were to either stain the raw wood, paint it black again, or leave it raw and have friends paint over it. Here is a poll for your opinions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot; src=&quot;//www.websitegoodies.com/poll.php?id=114229&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far Ive scraped some of the paint off the sides. It is very dry, it cracks off in some places when I’m lucky. I’ll be buying a chisel ASAP, an old pocket knife and some sandpaper isn’t cutting it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/img/goodwill-chest/post-goodwill-chest-side-sanded.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also cut out most of the old floral canvas on the inside, leaving the exposed wood. &lt;strong&gt;Very&lt;/strong&gt; dusty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/img/goodwill-chest/post-goodwill-chest-inner.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the electronics, I’d like to mount some sort of power to the inside and allow for the chest itself to plug in to a wall outlet for power. This way it can be run permanently during the winter, and turned on when needed in the summer. A power strip might be the easiest solution; a battery would be inconvenient for this application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan to put the speakers on both sides of the chest, mostly because I think it would look aesthetically pleasing. As of now, this is planned to be controlled by a raspberry pi with a wifi and bluetooth dongle so devices can connect, and it can stream. I may also look at separate solutions that avoid using an ARM processor, as it can be inconvenient due to most software being 32bit/64bit dependent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have no idea how this will turn out, or if I will need to throw it out. But for 13$ and some old parts, its worth a shot. I’ll be giving updates in new posts as I go.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Adam Musciano</name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">QR Guitar Experiment</title><link href="http://adammusciano.com/2017/01/04/qr-guitar-experiment/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="QR Guitar Experiment" /><published>2017-01-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-01-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://adammusciano.com/2017/01/04/qr-guitar-experiment</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://adammusciano.com/2017/01/04/qr-guitar-experiment/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;inception&quot;&gt;Inception&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first guitar was a beat up acoustic American Standard that had been through many years of not-so-great care. The nut was cracked, the body was badly scratched, and vastly changing temperatures caused the guitar to warp. Throughout the years, I ended up getting new guitars, and my first went to the wayside, left to hang in my room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first started driving, I had romanticized the idea of going throughout the country in my late great-step-grandmother’s brown Honda 03’ CRV that my family had jokingly named the “Polished Turd”. I felt like just driving for the sake of exploring wasn’t enough, and that I needed some sort of mission or goal for the trip. I wanted to go alone, and meet new people on the way – To share ideas, laughs, and music. So, to sum up all of those goals, I came up with the QR Guitar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-idea&quot;&gt;The Idea&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to create a “living” guitar – an instrument that would pick up history on it’s way wherever it went, and transmit it’s history to the people who saw it. So, I decided I would put quotes that were meaningful to me on the body of the guitar, and the names of the people who came up with them on the neck. By putting a QR Code on the pickguard, anyone with a smartphone could scan it to get more information. The QR Code led to &lt;a href=&quot;http://mooseprojects.wixsite.com/qrguitar&quot;&gt;a website I created&lt;/a&gt; that would document where the guitar has been, and who had played it. People who visited the website could share their experience with the guitar, giving my once old and bland guitar a new life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;working-on-the-guitar&quot;&gt;Working on the Guitar&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite Frankly, I had no idea what I was doing. I made every mistake possible, from misquoting people to sanding against the grain of the wood to spilling wood glue all over the body. Luckily, I learned along the way and didn’t make any mistakes that totally ruined the instrument. It taught me a lot, and in the end I was left with an acoustic guitar that had real, hard-earned character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/img/post-qrGuitar-GIF.gif&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;wheres-it-been&quot;&gt;Where’s it Been?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The QR Guitar has travelled with me throughout most of the east coast, which I could never have imagined happening. People are always receptive to the idea of the guitar and tend to ask questions, although not many end up playing it. Lately it has been hanging where it was years before on a wall, waiting for another adventure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;future-goals&quot;&gt;Future Goals?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the guitar’s main purpose is still relevant today, and could see myself giving it away someday. I would love to see someone take the guitar and travel to new places with it, meeting and influencing new and different people along the way. That would be the ultimate reward, to see the ‘living’ QR Guitar thriving in new environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to see what has happened with this guitar, please go to: &lt;a href=&quot;http://mooseprojects.wixsite.com/qrguitar&quot;&gt;http://mooseprojects.wixsite.com/qrguitar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Y2XEQ0lDrfg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Adam Musciano</name></author><summary type="html">Inception
My first guitar was a beat up acoustic American Standard that had been through many years of not-so-great care. The nut was cracked, the body was badly scratched, and vastly changing temperatures caused the guitar to warp. Throughout the years, I ended up getting new guitars, and my first went to the wayside, left to hang in my room.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">On the Future of VR</title><link href="http://adammusciano.com/2016/12/07/future-of-vr/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On the Future of VR" /><published>2016-12-07T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-12-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://adammusciano.com/2016/12/07/future-of-vr</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://adammusciano.com/2016/12/07/future-of-vr/">&lt;p&gt;While participating in &lt;a href=&quot;https://devpost.com/software/amuseing-game&quot;&gt;HackPSU Spring ‘16&lt;/a&gt;,
my team decided to stretch the idea of immersive gaming to another level. By combining other
bio-technologies such as EEG scanners and muscle movement sensors, our goal was to create a virtual
reality fighting game that used real-time actions and thoughts to affect game play. The player could
heal with a focused mind, attack with hand movement, and dodge with head movement. The game was fun
to make and engaging, yet ultimately led to my unease towards virtual reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://challengepost-s3-challengepost.netdna-ssl.com/photos/production/software_photos/000/373/970/datas/gallery.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Gameplay Screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;my-optimism&quot;&gt;My Optimism&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that the Virtual Reality may become one of the most consequential technologies that we have
seen as a society since the advent of the internet. Over the weekend, I had seen a
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=2&amp;amp;cad=rja&amp;amp;uact=8&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwid3b6TveHQAhXGeCYKHXeeCqQQtwIIHTAB&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DfW0KSHOR6wI&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNHCACR2o4tX9hsvl42aZIyRbmTTQw&amp;amp;sig2=3gTICaI7musggROY4-j1tw&amp;amp;bvm=bv.140496471,d.eWE&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;
of a VR Boxing simulation being played by professional boxers. They seemed to be impressed by the accuracy
of the game, which got me to thinking.. if a boxer could have his opponent’s characteristics programmed
into a simulation, that would be the most ideal sparring partner. There is little to no risk of injury
and unlimited amounts of practice – a dangerous combination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With VR becoming more convincing and more accessible, I believe that this type of technology will soon
enter our work place, our social lives, and our private lives. This type of progression will lead to new levels of optimization
and technical immersion. Just a month ago I heard about a &lt;a href=&quot;http://feelreal.com/&quot;&gt;new VR headset&lt;/a&gt;
that will incorporate heat, cooling, scents, and wind. In the near future, you could feel and smell the burning of a virtual campfire, or
the wind on a morning beach. (Nostalgic, I know.) This could also be applied to military training, emergency drills, and a multitude of
other practices that might be hard to replicate in the real world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;my-cynicism&quot;&gt;My Cynicism&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Virtual Reality &lt;del&gt;will&lt;/del&gt; &lt;strong&gt;could&lt;/strong&gt; tear our families apart, isolate us as individuals, and plague our societies with addiction.
Too harsh? Probably. But, I do think that virtual reality will force us as a society to face a new problem that stems from our
media consumption. Just as with the advent of television, then video games, then the internet, then streaming.. media usage spikes
with new technologies. Recently, our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.emarketer.com/Article/Growth-Time-Spent-with-Media-Slowing/1014042&quot;&gt;usage has slowed down&lt;/a&gt;,
to a point where it is only growing negligibly now. With the release of Google’s shot at virtual reality, I think VR is the new technology
that will cause a spike in media consumption. In fact, &lt;a href=&quot;https://netaddictionrecovery.com/home/virtual-reality/vr-addiction/576-virtual-reality-how-addictive-is-it.html&quot;&gt;there are already groups&lt;/a&gt;
helping users with their addictions to Virtual Reality.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Adam Musciano</name></author><summary type="html">While participating in HackPSU Spring ‘16,
my team decided to stretch the idea of immersive gaming to another level. By combining other
bio-technologies such as EEG scanners and muscle movement sensors, our goal was to create a virtual
reality fighting game that used real-time actions and thoughts to affect game play. The player could
heal with a focused mind, attack with hand movement, and dodge with head movement. The game was fun
to make and engaging, yet ultimately led to my unease towards virtual reality.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A New Blog!</title><link href="http://adammusciano.com/2016/12/05/making-a-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A New Blog!" /><published>2016-12-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-12-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://adammusciano.com/2016/12/05/making-a-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://adammusciano.com/2016/12/05/making-a-blog/">&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot;&gt;
  My name is Adam Musciano, and I'm a developer. I've decided to start a blog to act as a repository for my ideas,
  goals, and reflections. Thank you for reading!!

  &lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;br /&gt;

  &lt;iframe src=&quot;//giphy.com/embed/3o7TKnqKj5vE0kC0ik?html5=true&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;330&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; class=&quot;giphy-embed&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Adam Musciano</name></author><summary type="html">My name is Adam Musciano, and I'm a developer. I've decided to start a blog to act as a repository for my ideas,
  goals, and reflections. Thank you for reading!!</summary></entry></feed>
